Well, we are out here at the 2026 NFL
owners meetings. I am joined by Sports
Illustrated's Albert Breer and this is a
great place where you can mix and
mingle, get to get to know the GMs and
the head coaches a little bit better.
What has it been like for you so far for
this season in particular? I you know, I
say for me it's more just seeing people
at this point. Like I I don't know. This
is I mean, I've been doing this for over
20 years. So, you know, I know most of
the people.
You know, for me it's the face time is
really invaluable. That's actually
interesting. Like for me it goes back to
COVID and that year where
I I felt like I was at a a little bit of
an advantage because, you know, I do
have access to people. I remember coming
out of that and like going on my
training camp trip and seeing people
face-to-face and how it just jumped out
at me how different it is actually being
in front of people. Sure. And so, like I
I've really learned to value that as
much as I can and it is an important
thing. Like it's even if it's not
someone new or somebody you don't know.
And there are still people like, you
know, I'll say I need to get to know
this person or that person that might be
coming up. Maybe it's a coordinator,
maybe it's a, you know, a scouting
director. Um it's just as important to
kind of maintain your old relationships.
So, that's, you know, a lot of what I
try to do when I'm here.
>> Right. And I know you have some
relationships with the Viking staff and
that you follow the team pretty closely.
Free agency, how do you think they were
able to balance the salary cap as well
as their positions of need? Yeah, you
know, I think it's interesting with some
of the, you know, the big picture
things. Obviously Ryan Kelly's, you
know, departure, his retirement, is
something that is going to be a topic
for them going into OTAs and and
ultimately training camp. And I look at
like them as still having business to
do, you know. And I and they weren't as
active this year as they were last year,
but what happens with Jonathan Greenard?
You know, obviously he wanted a raise,
was given [music] permission to go out
and find out what was out there for him.
Um you know, if a team was willing to
give him a raise and come back with
something of value, they would think
about it. There's a tendency sometimes
to overreact in the first couple of days
of free agency and it's just one piece
of the off season. And I think for a
team like the Vikings that wasn't I
super active,
you know, over those first couple of
days. Um there is a focus on some other
things and they certainly have some more
business they still need to get done.
>> Well, one of the things they wanted to
do this off season was make their
quarterback room more competitive. And
through free agency, they added Kyler
Murray, a former first-round draft pick.
How do you see Kyler fitting what coach
O'Connell's offense loves to do so well?
Well, I would say, you know, I think
there are a couple things here. I think
number one, um
based on where they are with JJ and
wanting to add competition to that room,
um it kind of goes back a year cuz their
initial intention was to have
competition in that room with their
effort to bring Sam Darnold back and
bring and then bring Daniel Jones back.
And obviously those guys
a better opportunity in Seattle and and
and Indianapolis to not just win a
starting job in 2025, but then be the
long-term answer. And both those guys
were able to accomplish that at least
for the time being. So, like how do you
find somebody who is going to have their
best opportunity to come there and
compete for a job. And so, I think they
kind of went back a couple years and
it's, you know, what they did with Sam
Darnold. And then I think seeing Kyler
as somebody who still had, [music]
you know, still had some room to grow,
still had some ceiling to chase. Um you
know, their experience their past
experience with building offenses for
different quarterbacks. Um
you know, to swing it back around to
what you originally asked. Like I I
think one of Kevin's strengths is that
he's going to play the strengths of his
quarterbacks. So, I don't think this is
so much going to be
Kyler's fit for Minnesota. I think it's
going to be how Kevin fits the offense
to Kyler. And and that part of it's
going to be really interesting cuz Kyler
he's had good players around him. He had
DeAndre Hopkins in his prime in
Arizona, but I don't think he ever had
the balance of skill players around him
that are in Minnesota. What do you think
makes Kyler stand out as a as an obvious
choice to to be a competitive person in
that room?
>> I think like without question it's the
ability to extend plays, the ability to,
you know, keep plays alive and then
>> [music]
>> um you know, it's almost like you have
the second play and then you have the
third play. It's the first play as
called, the second play is when he
breaks the pocket and he's on the edge
and now you've got your receivers in a
scramble situation, which is going to
create opportunities for guys like
Jefferson and Addison and Hockenson that
maybe weren't there before. And then you
have potentially the third play, which
he could just take off and rip off 20,
30 yards on his own on a dime. And so,
it's a it's definitely a different type
of quarterback than what they've had in
the past. Um and I I would be pretty
confident that Kevin's going to be able
to fit the offense to him.
>> Right. When you look at what the
Viking's needs are as we approach the
draft in about a month, where do you
think they go? I mean, they have nine
picks, so they've got, you know, they've
got some wiggle room. They can go for
different positions throughout all the
different rounds. Is there something you
see as their top need there they would
want to target in the first round?
>> they're pretty balanced. I mean, I think
you always want to add offensive
lineman. So, it wouldn't surprise me to
see them go down that road. And I think,
you know, somewhere in the first three
or four rounds, like you're going to see
one or two offensive lineman.
Um and that's smart business. I think
it's always good to invest in that area.
Um you know, safety, Harrison Smith's
obviously getting older. So, Caleb Downs
won't be there, but, you know, Adonai
Eagbar from from Oregon, the Toledo kid
who's kind of the height-weight-speed
guy. Um could those guys be
possibilities?
Uh the good thing about where they're at
is it this is
this draft isn't great at the very top
just based on
what you would look for in a prototype,
right? Like there's not a Julio Jones
receiver. There's not a Joe Alt or Penei
Sewell left tackle. There's not a Myles
Garrett, Jadeveon Clowney, Julius
Peppers defensive end. Okay. There's not
a Pat Surtain corner, but
once you get past that, there's good
depth and there's good balance. And so,
um you know, I think the Vikings are in
a spot where over the first three
rounds,
you can
you can get multiple starters and you
can get multiple starters at premium
spots. Um so, again, they're not going
to be the it's not going to be, you
know, it's it's not going to be Julio.
It's not going to be, you know, the no
doubt about it Julius Peppers. Like that
guy looks like he was built in a lab to
play that position, but but there are
there are good players there that
they'll be able to dig out. All right.
Well, thank you for your time, Albert.
Enjoy the weather, the beautiful Arizona
weather out here. I know you're an East
Coaster, so enjoy. Well, this time
zone's making me a little tired. I know
you're kind of feeling it, too. Yeah,
absolutely.
>> Thank you so much.
>> it.